Greetings to all the brothers.  My name is
Satyendra and today I have come to share with you a
dispute that I am having with ICICI Bank.
I had taken a credit card from ICICI Bank.
I had taken that card in 8th February 2024 and on
8th February 2025, I had requested to close that card.
Ok?  I sent you that
request on February 8th.
Ok?  You can see that it is clearly
written that we have registered your cancellation
card cancellation request.  They have
given me the serial number and the date mentioned
that it will be completed in seven working days.
Ok?  After that I received
this mail.  A confirmation mail arrives stating
that the requested Instant ICICI
Bank Credit Card 88 has been closed.
And the FD balance, that is, the
card was against the FD.  So whatever
they had to recover from the FD,
they recovered it and deposited all that money in my savings account.
Ok?  Now the
concern with me is that I start
getting calls after 6 months that I have
not paid the credit card bill.  So,
first I ignore it thinking it is a fake call.
Then after some time I start
getting messages.  So I go to the branch.
After going to the branch I ask why
I am getting these mails.  Whereas no
card is showing in my iPhone.
Nor is it showing me anything that
I can search for.  Oh, then you
help me.  So the help he gave me was that
he told me the card number and that there are 8 cards.
It is outstanding and I don't
know why it was saved.  These people told me
that one of your EMIs remained pending.  Whereas
how did the EMI of FD card continue?  That was a bank
award.  Now what do I have to survive,
what do I have to survive?  My
frustration is that I made the first
complaint around November 8.
After that, ah, around November 24th.
After that, I am taking continuous follow up from 24th November.  I am going to the
branch.
I am making two visits to the branch every week.  There are
two mails every week.
I escalated this complaint at every level.
Meaning at every level.
Even after that I am not being heard.
That's why I had to come on social media also.
So the concern was that the total matter is worth
₹800.  Ok?  I also tried to
pay this bill.  So let me
tell you what's happening to me.
When I'm trying to fill it out completely.
I'll give you that too, Clitty.
Look, just look for a second,
he has written this, which means I
told him to give me the NOC for this.
When I came to know that this was a card and I had already
closed this card,
I asked for NOC from them.  So they
said we have closed the instant ICICI
Bank credit card 88 ah service
request number and
they told that your FD is valid, all the money has been
returned but the record on Edge is
showing some outstanding amount of ₹945 on it.  Now
it is writing that we have sent a credit
card statement on your registered email ID
which includes a QR code on the
credit card you can pay by scanning the
QR code.  Ok?  So let me tell you now.
One second.
This is my credit card statement.
And this QR code that you were talking about, I will
scan it with another mobile and
show you what error is coming.  Now when
I am scanning this QR code
from Paytm or any other application the error is same.
Ok?  You are trying to send money to
an invalid UPI ID.  Please try with
valid UPI ID.  Now the problem that I am facing is
that neither I am able to
pay that bill
nor I am able to close my card
and the report that these people have filed in my civil,
I will show that to you
one second, now I did not pay their ₹800,
because of not paying those ₹800 my
civil approx
dropped by 80 points.  Ok?  I have created
disputes and multiple disputes for this.  Let
me show you that too.
These people are repeatedly denying this.
Whereas they themselves have admitted in the mail
that we have closed that card on 11th.
He has already accepted this.
I have already done it for two-three disputes.
Still,
I will show you the replies that these people give.  In
this reply, I sent them
three queries.  Firstly, I
submitted a query to make the current balance zero.
Firstly, I asked them to make the current balance zero.
Firstly, I said make the date of
closing the card 112 and the amount overdue make it
zero.  So this is the one which is
rejecting it again and again and
what it is saying in the rejection is that brother customer
requested to modify dispute value
cannot be served since the value has been computed captured assigned
correctly
in the system.  Ok?
He has given the same reply in all three.  Whereas
on the mail these people are saying that they have
closed the credit card on 11th
and as per RBI guidelines they should
close it within 7 days and if they do
not close it within 7 days then there
is a fine of ₹100 per day on them, but still what is
happening with me is a
huge harassment and the
disadvantages of credit card are there in India
which no one is talking about,
I felt that I should tell them a little because there is
no one to listen here.  I
complained to the nodal officer of Trans Union.
Complained at every level of Trans Union.  I complained at every level of ICICI Bank.  I have
also filed a complaint with the RBI.  And
I am doing it on social media also.  Let's see
how many days it takes to get cured.
I will definitely update you that
my first complaint was on November 24th, 8th.  November 8
to December 8, January 8 and February 8.  I've had three
months.  Now I will see how many more
months it will take to get it fixed and I will
definitely give you an update on it.  Thank you to all the
brothers who gave their time to
help me and please retweet this tweet
and
share it with all your friends who
believe a lot in credit cards and
say that credit cards are very good.  So
everyone should know these consequences that I had to take a personal loan.
I am not able to take that.  The
loans that I had to take, the loans that I had to take for my needs,
I
can say that my financial condition has become completely
disabled.
So you guys share it with all your friends.
Thank you very much.  Hmm